momslikeme.com 2011-10-07

# USA MomsLikeMe.com -- Privacy Policy - Where local moms go to get advice, share photos, ideas and more!

##  USA MomsLikeMe.com Privacy Notice

Last Updated: April 7, 2011

Thank you for visiting MomsLikeMe.com. We know that you care how information about you is used and shared, and this Privacy Notice is intended to give you an understanding of our privacy practices.

This Privacy Notice outlines the types of information that we gather about you while you are using this website, and the ways in which we use and share this information. This Privacy Notice does not apply to any information you may provide to us, or that we may collect, offline and/or through other means (for example via telephone or through the mail).

Please read this Privacy Notice carefully. By visiting and using this site, you agree that your use of our site, and any dispute over our online privacy practices, is governed by this Privacy Notice and our Terms of Service. Because the Web is an evolving medium, we may need to change our Privacy Notice at some point in the future, in which case we'll post the revised Privacy Notice on this website and update the "Last Updated" date to reflect the date of the changes. By continuing to use this site after we post any such changes, you accept the Privacy Notice as modified.

## Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits any of our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:

Mark Faris  
Online Privacy Coordinator  
MomsLikeMe.com  
Gannett Law Department  
7950 Jones Branch Drive  
McLean, VA 22107 

## How We Collect and Use Information

We may collect and store information, including personally-identifiable information (such as your name, postal address or email address) or other information, that you voluntarily supply to us while on our site. Some examples of this type of information include information that you electronically submit when you contact us with questions, information that you post in discussion areas, groups, marketplace or other community posting and social networking areas on our site, and information that you electronically submit when you complete an online registration form to access and use certain features of our site. We also may ask for information (including a credit card number and other financial information) from those users who make purchases or have payment transactions on our site. If you decline to supply or provide us with certain information while using the site, you may not be able to use or participate in some or all of the features offered through the site.

We also collect, through a variety of technologies and practices, and store non-personally identifiable information that is generated automatically as you navigate through the site. For example, we may collect information about your computer's connection to the Internet, which allows us, among other things, to improve the delivery of our web pages to you and to measure traffic on the site. We also may use a standard feature found in browser software called a "cookie" to enhance your experience with the site. Cookies are small files that your web browser places on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes. By showing how and when visitors and registered users use the site, cookies help us deliver more relevant advertisements to users, identify how many unique users visit us, and track user interests, trends and patterns. They also prevent you from having to re-enter your preferences on certain areas of the site where you may have entered preference information before. For example, if you select the "Remember Me" option when you log in to the site, we will use cookies to recognize you so you won't need to reenter your email address and password the next time you visit the site. We also may use web beacons (single-pixel graphic files also known as "transparent GIFs") or other technology to access cookies and to count users who visit the site or open HTML-formatted email messages.

If you want to limit the non-personally identifiable information that is automatically collected while you use our site, most Web browsers allow you to disable certain functionality or set certain privacy settings. For example, to disable cookies using Internet Explorer, select "Internet Options" under the Tools menu and click on "Privacy." Select "High" or "Block All Cookies." To disable cookies using Mozilla Firefox, select "Options" under the "Tools" menu. If you choose to disable cookies or turn off other functionality, you may not be able to use or participate in some or all of the features offered through the site. 

The information we collect may be collected directly by us, or it may be collected by a third-party website hosting provider, or another third-party service provider, on our behalf.

We use the information we collect from you while you are using the site in a variety of ways, including, for example, to process your registration request, provide you with services and communications that you have requested, send you email updates and other communications, customize features and advertising that appear on the site, deliver our site content to you, measure site traffic, measure user interests and traffic patterns, and improve the site and the services and features offered via the site.

In addition, we may use any information submitted by or collected from you via the site for any purpose related to the site, including to contact you for customer service purposes, to inform you of important changes or additions to our site or the services offered over our site, and to send you administrative notices and any other communications that we believe may be of interest to you.

We also may provide your information to our affiliates or to third parties, including our third party service providers and contractors, for purposes related to site administration and other services. For example, if you use a credit or debit card to complete a transaction on our site, we may share your personal information and credit card number with a credit card processing and/or a fulfillment company in order to complete your transaction, or such service provider(s) may collect that information from you directly, on our behalf.

If you do not wish your personally identifiable information to be used or shared for these purposes, send a letter to the Online Privacy Coordinator, whose contact information is listed at the end of this Privacy Notice.

For information about use of your information by us and by third-party advertising service providers for advertising, see the section "Data Collected in Connection with Ad Serving and Targeting."

Our site also includes links to other websites and provides access to products and services offered by third parties, whose privacy policies we do not control. When you access another website or purchase products or services from a third-party, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting or the provider of such products or services.

We also make some content, products and services available through our site through cooperative relationships with third-party providers, where the brands of our provider partner appear on the site in connection with such content, products and/or services. We may share with our provider partner any information you provide, or that is collected, in the course of visiting any pages that are made available in cooperation with our provider partner. In some cases, the provider partner may collect information from you directly, in which cases the privacy policy of our provider partner may apply to the provider partner's use of your information. The privacy policy of our provider partners may differ from ours. If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of one of our provider partners, you should contact the provider partner directly for more information.

If you provide us with a friend's email address in connection with the "invite others to join," "share" or "tell a friend" features that we offer on our site, we will automatically send your friend an email with, as applicable, an invitation to join our site, or the photo, story, coupon or other item that you have asked us to share with your friend. We will not use your friend's email address for any purpose other than sending the communication(s) that you have requested unless your friend registers to use our site and provides the same email address to us directly as part of the registration process.

Please be aware that we may occasionally release information about our visitors and registered users if required to do so by law or if, in our business judgment, such disclosure is reasonably necessary: (a) to comply with legal process; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service; or (c) to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of our site, us, our affiliates, our officers, directors, employees, representatives, our licensors, other users, and/or the public.

Please also note that as our business grows, we may buy or sell various assets. In the unlikely event that we sell some or all of our assets, or our site is acquired by another company, information about our site users may be among the transferred assets. 

## Information You Post to Discussion Areas, Groups or Other Community Posting or Social Networking Areas on Our Site, or Disclose in Your Public Profile

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily make your personal information or other private information available for viewing by other users or third parties online - for example in your public profile or in discussion areas, groups or other community posting or social networking areas of our site - that information can be seen, collected and used by others besides us. We cannot be responsible for any third-party use of such information. You can communicate with other registered users of the site, and they can communicate with you, using the site's private messaging ("pm") service, without disclosing email addresses. But again, if you make your email address or any other personally identifying information part of your public profile, or post it in any public discussion forum or group, that information will be publicly available, and we will not be able to control how it may be used.

The general discussion areas that are available on our site (under the "Discussions" tab) are public — anyone can participate, post and read others' postings. The "groups" on our site (each of which includes a discussion area, a photo gallery and an events calendar) are created by other registered users and may be either public or private. Public groups are visible to all users of the site, and any registered user of the site can post a comment to a public group and will automatically become a member of that group. Private groups are hidden from the general users of the site and will not appear in search results — only users that are invited to participate by the group's creator, and our site administrators, can participate, post and read other group members' postings in a private group.

We also may allow advertisers to create discussion groups relating to their brands or products so that users who are interested in those brands, products or services can benefit from the information the advertisers post to the group and can participate in discussions with other users who are interested in the same brands, products or services. Advertisers may post product information to these groups, post information about exclusive savings and offers, or simply solicit customer feedback. If you choose to become a member of an advertiser-created group, that advertiser will have access to all of the information you post to the group, and will be able to see your activities within the group and how you use and interact with the group. Also we may syndicate the group to another site. Your posting will appear in the original discussion group to which you are posting it (i.e., the advertiser discussion group on MomsLikeMe.com), and also will appear in the other third-party discussion groups. The posting will be displayed in those other discussion groups as if you posted it to that group or website originally and will identify you by the same username or other identification associated with your original posting. Similarly, the advertiser-created discussion groups on our site may from time to time contain postings that have been posted to those groups by members of similar discussion groups on third-party websites.

Our site also may employ a sharing or recommending feature that allows you to share your photos, calendar entries, discussion forum and group postings, profile information and other materials that you post to the site with the site users and groups of your choosing. You also can use these features to move postings, photos or calendar items from one group to another. If you choose to share a photo, posting or other item using this feature, your posting will appear in the original discussion forum or group to which you are posting it, and also will appear in the other discussion areas or groups that you have selected for sharing. The posting will be displayed in those other discussion areas and groups as if you posted it to that forum or group originally.

When you upload photos or other materials, post calendar entries, or post messages to discussion areas or groups, you also will have the option of sharing those postings and materials with people outside of our site (i.e., friends of yours who may not be site members), and you may designate such items as being "shareable" by other site users. If you designate such items as being "shareable" by other site users, those users can in turn distribute or share your items to their own friends and groups within our site, and/or with persons outside of our site. Even if you do not designate such items as being "shareable," other users can "cut" or "copy" or utilize other means to use your items. 

## Data Collected in Connection with Ad Serving and Targeting

We may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies, and/or a third-party ad serving software, to collect non-personally identifiable information about site users and site activity, and we may use this information to, among other things, serve targeted advertisements on this site. The information collected allows us to analyze how visitors and registered users use the site and to track user interests, trends and patterns, thus allowing us to deliver more relevant advertisements to users.

We also may use third-party service providers to target and serve some of the advertisements you see on the pages of our site, and these providers may use their own cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information from our site. These service providers may use that information, sometimes in conjunction with similar non-personally identifiable information gathered through other websites, to deliver advertisements on this site, and on other websites that participate in our service providers' advertising networks, that are tailored to match the perceived interests of consumers. This information also may be used to help measure and research an advertisement's effectiveness, or for other purposes.

The data collected in connection with the ad serving and ad targeting on our site does not identify you personally and does not include your name, address, email address or telephone number, but it may include the IP address of your computer.

The use and collection of information by third-party advertising service providers is governed by the relevant third party's privacy policy and is not covered by our Privacy Notice. If you would like more information about the information collection practices of a particular service provider, or if you would like more information on how to opt out of a service provider's information collection practices, please click here.

## Children's Privacy Statement

This children's privacy statement explains our practices with respect to the online collection and use of personal information from children under the age of 13, and provides important information regarding their rights under federal law with respect to such information.

  * This site is not directed to children under the age of 13 and we do NOT knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 as part of the site. We screen users who wish to provide personal information in order to prevent users under the age of 13 from providing such information. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of 13 as part of the site, we will delete such information from our records.

  * Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 via the site, we also do NOT knowingly distribute such information to third parties.

  * We do NOT knowingly allow children under the age of 13 to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information through the site.

  * Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 via the site, we do NOT condition the participation of a child under 13 in the site's online activities on providing personally identifiable information.

## How To Modify Your Account Information and Settings

If you are a registered member of our site, you can make changes to your account information, account settings and preferences by logging in to the site and using the account tools available via the site. You also may adjust certain privacy settings associated with your account to control which portions of your user profile can be viewed by other users. When you update your account or profile information, we may keep a copy of the prior version for our records.

If you have any questions about modifying your account or preference information, please read our "FAQs" or visit the "About Us" portion of our site and send us an email using the email address provided.

## Storage of Information

All information we gather on our site is stored within a database to which only we and our hosting services provider are provided access. However, as effective as the reasonable security measures implemented by us may be, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our site's servers or databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

## Questions Regarding Privacy

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, our privacy practices, or your dealings with us, you can contact:

Mark Faris  
Online Privacy Coordinator  
MomsLikeMe.com  
Gannett Law Department  
7950 Jones Branch Drive  
McLean, VA 22107
